Jim Sahin

Mobile: 0423 593 036

Kensington, Melbourne VIC 3031 E-mail: cemdenizsahin@gmail.com

Full rights to work in Australia LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cemdenizsahin

Professional Summary

A professional with a Masters in Geomatics Engineering and over two years work experience in geographic information systems (GIS), geospatial analyses and site surveying. Skills in cartography, photogrammetry and geodesy. Energetic and highly motivated team player. International experience managing large, complex regional and local GIS / remote sensing datasets. Additional skills include project management, consulting and procurement, development of sales proposals, liaison with national government, university and private sector stakeholders, research and development and staff management

Skills Summary

General Skills

- Highly people oriented, customer-focused and solutions driven
- Strong project management and organisational skills, capable of managing different projects at the same time
- Well-developed negotiation, interpersonal and leadership skills
- Ability to create solutions under stress
- Focussed on industry best practice and innovation
- Experienced in project proposals, tendering procedures, service and work contracts
- Ability to work very well within a team environment as well as working independently
- Strong analytical and problem solving skills and resourceful

Computer Skills

 ArcGIS, GlobalMapper, ER Mapper, ENVI, Erdas, NetCAD, 12d Model, Geomagic, Lecia Cyclone, QGIS, Microsoft Office

Professional Experience

Assistant Engineering Surveyor

Nov 2016- Jan 2017

Heavy Construction Solutions, Melbourne, Australia

HCS is one of Australia's most diverse engineering surveying businesses providing Survey Management and UAV solutions for major construction projects throughout Australia and South East Asia. HCS work with the world's largest engineering construction companies to deliver exceptional value and quality of work (www.heavycs.com.au)

Responsibilities

- Supported site surveyors to gather survey field data (using total station and GPS)
- Prepared work sheets for engineering surveys and applying all relevant checks to ensure quality of computed work
- Assisted in the training of staff, maintenance of equipment and office records and assisting in the development of new techniques and procedures.

Project Experience: CityLink Tulla Widening Project

HCS has been awarded the Engineering Surveying Services contract by Lend Lease for the \$250 million Tullamarine Freeway upgrade between Melbourne Airport and Bulla Road

1

Geomatics Engineer

Jul 2015- Jun 2016

Technical Sales and Customer Support

NIK System, Istanbul, Turkey

NIK System is the largest specialist remote sensing solutions company in Turkey. It has the widest range of satellite imagery products, but also gives technical support to private and government clients who need assistance to analyse imagery. Additionally, NIK is the distributor of the software that can be used for processing satellite imagery (www.nik.com.tr)

Responsibilities

- Analysed and provided technical report on satellite imagery for over 200 national and international clients such as Fugro Maps and TUBITAK
- Promoted the company's satellite imagery, software, airborne and hyperspectral cameras and LiDAR systems to private and public clients
- Provided technical support and consultancy on the use of imagery
- Represented the company at conferences, trade shows, fairs and industry functions
- Developed and maintained sales relationships with potential, existing clients and vendor partners including Airbus, Japan Space System and DigitalGlobe
- Delivered weekly and monthly risk and sales status reports to company directors

Achievements

- Personally managed confidential, commercially sensitive contracts up to AUD\$0.25M e.g. confidential defence organisation
- Maintained high levels of customer satisfaction which resulted in renewal of future sales agreements
- Expanded international sales by 30% by negotiating a new deal with a satellite image provider partner in China
- Organised a campaign which assisted the company to exceed target sales of midresolution imagery by 20% in 2015

GIS Analyst Mar 2014 - May 2015

National Innovation and Research Centre for Geographical Information Technologies (GIT Centre), Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey

GIT centre with the objective to establish a geospatial research and development centre to develop and provide location based services (LBS). It's projects cover disciplines in urban development and planning, environmental sciences, public welfare and safety, and land use/land cover monitoring and analysis (www.cbs.itu.edu.tr)

Responsibilities

- Provided GIS and desktop (online) mapping support for a range of internal and external consulting projects.
- Worked on flood data management project
- Collated site GIS data (mobile mapping) for the ITU online Campus Map, an interactive map for university users
- Supported development of large national GIS database from the Turkish Statistical Institute (national GIS sources and statistical data e.g. population, transport etc.)
- Managed and participated in fieldwork and data collection of special and geographical information
- Acquisition, integration, maintenance and delivery of spatial data
- Analysed, rendered and presented this information visually in an online map form
- Supported the ITU Campus LiDAR Scanning program implementation
- Organized technical and academic events within the university such as the 27th International Geodetic Student Meeting (2014) held in Istanbul, Turkey
- Represented the centre in national and international meetings and conferences

Achievement

• Edited and wrote 2 chapters for a GIS lecture book under the supervision of the centre's assistant manager for Afyon Kocatepe University

Assistant Event Coordinator

Sep-Nov 2013

17th International Symposium on Environmental Pollution and Its Impact on Life in the Mediterranean Region- (MESAEP) Mediterranean Scientific Association of Environmental Protection, Istanbul Turkey

MESAEP was founded in 1979 in Germany as a non-profit scientific organization. The objective of the MESAEP was to provide a forum for interested persons from the field of the environmental sciences carrying out research related to chemical contamination and the other sources of pollution in the Mediterranean environment,

Responsibilities:

 Supported the planning, organisation, registration of participants including transport and accommodation and closure of the event

Professional Qualifications

Master of Science in Geomatics Engineering

2016

Istanbul Technical University (ITU), Turkey

My thesis focused on the use of GIS technologies in mapping water consumption, entitled "Determining Water Consumption with Help of Geographical Information Systems in the Base of Hotels; A case study from Istanbul". This work demonstrated that, through use of GIS, future hotel water consumption requirements could be more easily analysed to assist in future regional water planning

Bachelor of Science in Geomatics Engineering

2014

Istanbul Technical University (ITU), Turkey

My undergraduate thesis investigated a range of modelling methods to analyse the effects of different land features on emergency flooding events, using terrestrial LiDAR technologies

Erasmus Exchange Program in Rural and Surveying Engineering

2012

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

Professional Membership

Union of Chambers of Turkish Engineers and Architects - Chamber of Survey and Cadastre

Leadership Experience

President, Board of Directors: Geodesy and Photogrammetry Student Club. Managed up to ten staff and represented up to 300 members.

Secretary, Board of Directors: Erasmus Student Network (ESN). Events co-ordinator, student secretary.

Volunteer, ITU Social & Cultural Centre's Assistance: Organised social events and courses for new students

Founder of ITUVISION Song Contest. Founder and lead organiser of University hosted song contest

Conference Attendance

- The World Cadastre Summit, Congress & Exhibition (2015) Istanbul -Turkey
- Turkey Surveying Scientific and Technical Conference- (2011,2015) Ankara Turkey
- International Geodetic Student Meeting (2014) Istanbul Turkey
- European Youth Event (2014) Strasbourg France (Representing ESN Turkey)
- Mediterranean Scientific Association of Environmental Protection -(2013) Istanbul -Turkey
- Erasmus Student Network Balkan Section Meeting (2013) / Skopje Macedonia
- International Geodetic Student Meeting (2013) / Wroclaw Poland

Referees

Available upon on request